I'm Ingrid, a partner in our DC office.
As you heard from other leaders, problem solving — or the process
by which we make decisions — is a core element of leadership.
So, what does great problem solving look like?
When the problem solving is okay,
you're probably getting to an answer to the problem.
It may even be a reasonably good answer —
but you're not getting the best answer.
And oftentimes what differentiates the okay versus the great
is whether you are leveraging the collective power of the group.
Oftentimes one individual — in many cases
the leader of the group solving the problem —
takes a disproportionate share
of the problem-solving burden.
They may be imposing their own view on how to structure
the problem and go about the analysis.
I think the great examples of problem solving are around
how you get the most out of everybody involved.
And one of the tricks, as a problem-solving leader,
is to understand how to do that.
If you're in an environment where you're working
through a problem with a number of people,
it is probably more important to actually formalize
and put on a sheet of paper:
What is our problem? What are the constraints?
Who are the stakeholders we need to align?
And how are we structuring the problem to enable everybody
to eventually agree and align on the approach to get to the right solution?
Conversely, if you're working through a problem and everybody's
saying the same things, it may even be the right answer.
But in those cases, as a problem-solving leader,
you want to think about how you can push that thinking.
Do you want to introduce the concept
of a red team and a blue team?
Do you want to appoint somebody — even yourself — as a devil's advocate,
to really test whether the idea you're all thinking is the right or best answer?
Being a collaborative problem-solving leader is great not only to get
to the right answer, the best answer one can, or the answer as quickly as possible.
It has a second benefit, which is the impact of the collaboration
and getting everybody really bought into that solution.